

# Zin Lin Htun

# System Engineer

Experienced IT system engineer in Microsoft365 and Azure Cloud administration, Virtualization, Windows, and Linux server installation and administration in IT and banking, retail environments. Great technical team member with positive attitude contributing high levels of expertise in system and network infrastructure. Over 5 years working experience with Microsoft, Red Hat, Oracle, VMware, Cisco, and Juniper versed in system, network security, protocols, and software.

## **Contact Details & Information**

- Email: zinlinhtunm2l@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/zin-lin-htun
- Address: 28Woodlands Crescent, #05-19, NORTHOAKS, Singapore, 738085.
- WhatsApp: +6584242890
- Nationality: Myanmar
- Language: Burmese (Native), English (Advanced)
- Expected Salary: \$\$5500 Negotiable.
- Reason for Leaving: Looking for career growth and a better workplace.
- Visa Status: SPASS
- Availability: Two Months' Notice

# **Experience**

MAY 2023- CURRENT

**System Engineer** 

#### YTL PowerSeraya Pte Limited

- Responsible for Azure Cloud and on premise infra operations covering virtual machines, backup, and SAN storage.
- Responsible for provisioning, installation, configuration, troubleshooting and maintenance of virtual machines (Wintel and Linux) and applications.
- Responsible for VMware Esxi, V Center related with on premise VMs administration.
- AD, Office 365, and Share Folders administration.
- Responsible for PAM Wallix Bastion administration.
- Setup and configure new Active Directory; migrate DHCP scope together with Network team.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to plan and execute the migration of legacy systems to modern cloud-based solutions to ensure system downtime is kept to minimum.
- Backup servers using Veeam 11 (on premise VMs to Cloud) and Azure Backup (Azure VMs)

- Performed system upgrades and patch management to ensure the security and stability of servers and workstation.
- Together with team review, plan, implement and maintaining security policies and procedures together with Security team.
- Coordinated disaster recovery drills (Azure ASR) and tested backup systems, ensuring business continuity in case of critical incidents.
- Implemented automated configuration management using tools Ansible, PowerShell scripts & batch scripting reducing manual errors and streamlining system deployments.
- Perform day-to-day system or application job request and support.
- Support basic Microsoft SQL administration on ad-hoc basis.
- Manage and co-ordinate with third party vendors for OS/ software patching, support, and troubleshooting.
- Ensure availability and continuity of infrastructures services.
- Proactively monitor using WhatsUp Gold (WUG) and maintain system standards.
- Plan and co-ordinate monthly or ad-hoc patching with various stakeholders.
- Involved in incident, problem, change and service request management.
- Create and maintain documentation for operational procedures and IT policies.

JAN 2021- APRIL 2023

#### **System Engineer**

#### Myanma Apex Bank (MAB)

- Wintel (Windows Server2008/2012/2016/2019) and Linux (Red Hat/Solaris/Rocky/CentOS) installation, administration, implementation, and troubleshooting.
- Responsible for Azure Cloud and on premise infra operations covering virtual machines, backup, and SAN storage.
- Users and File, Folder management such as permission, user account lock, unlock or deletion. DNS Server, Web Server, NFS, iSCSI Administration for both Linux and Windows Servers.
- Microsoft 365 and Azure Administration (Outlook Email, Microsoft Team, OneDrive, MS Team, and Share Point). Provide daily support for over 800 Office365 and Domain users related to several issues.
- VMware (vSphere 6.5 & Esxi 6.5) and Oracle Virtualization Administration VM creation and deletion, VM hardware and network management, regular maintenance, and VM monitoring.
- ❖ Infobip (SMS & Email Blasting Provider) Portal Administration and troubleshooting.
- AD Domain Servers (ADDS, GPO, DHCP, DNS, ADFS, ADCS, WSUS and other service management), Mail Relay, FTP, SFTP and SMB Servers Administration and troubleshooting.
- Daily Operational Support, backup process and monitoring for servers, jump hosts, storage, and network infrastructure in Datacenter and DR via remote or onsite.
- Document Management System (Oracle Web Server Content) Administration.
- \* Ticketing System (Manage Engine) administration users on account creation, template and flow setup, report management and provide training for users how to use ticketing system.
- Assist to Database Team related to SQL, Oracle 12c and other middleware.

AUGUST 2018 - DEC 2020

System and Network Support Technician

#### Myanma Apex Bank (MAB)

- \* Technical Support for End Users and Branches related to daily IT system and network issues.
- Provide technical training for users in HO and branches if any new technology is needed to use.

- Assist System and Network Engineers or Assistant Technicians related to system and network (LAN, WAN, Wi-Fi, Servers, and Storage) setup, administration, and troubleshooting.
- Printer, Scanner, Door Access, Fingerprint and CCTV network setup, troubleshooting and maintenance for Head Office and Branches.
- Installing, Maintenance and replacement for DC DR hardware and User PCs such as RAM, Hard Disk, Raid Controller, CPU, Power Supply etc.
- Responsible for Daily, Weekly, Monthly Backup and monitoring process for Servers and Storage.
- ❖ Participate as a technical support team member in various IT projects.

#### **Skills**

- VMware, Microsoft Hypervisor and Oracle Virtualization
- Windows and Linux Server Administration
- System and Network Troubleshooting
- Active Directory and Domain administration
- Microsoft 365 and Azure Cloud Administration

### **Education**

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) – Jan 2017

**West Yangon Technological University** 

Bachelor of Technology (Mechanical) - Jan 2016

**West Yangon Technological University** 

Diploma In Information Technology (IQN-UK) - May 2019

**Credit Rated by Edinburgh Napier University** 

Grade: SCQF Level (7), EQF Level (5)

# **Certifications**

- Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate (AZ-104) 2023
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (MCSE: Core Infrastructure) 2019
- ❖ Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA: Windows Server 2016) − 2019
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) 2020
- ❖ Juniper Network Certified Internet Associate x 2 (JNCIA-Junos & JNCIA-Sec) − 2020
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) 2022
- Microsoft Certified: Compliance, Security, and Identity Fundamentals (SC-900) 2022
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator Course Completion (Kode Kloud) 2022
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate 2023
- Linux and Private Cloud Administration on IBM Power System Specialization 2023